César Garro-Marín

Ph.D Candidate • Economics • Boston University

(§) (857) 425-9404 • □ cesarlgm@bu.edu • □ cesargarromarin.com • cesarlgm

About me

Ph.D candidate in Economics with a strong background in data analysis and causal inference. Over 8 years experience in Stata and R. Worked in teams on multiple projects contributing to the project development & management, as well as data collection, coding, statistical & econometric analysis.

Boston University

2019 - Graduate Student Researcher — Research Assistant

Used large datasets to study gender inequality & local labor markets, earnings inequality in US academia, & how people invest in skills. Findings demonstrate the importance of birthplace & local labor markets in shaping labor force participation and outcomes.

Created & oversaw multiple research projects on labor and development economics Worked with large census and survey data from multiple countries Devised and estimated reduced-form causal research designs Structurally estimated general-equilibrium models of the labor market Presented findings in internal departmental seminars as well as international conferences

2020 - Project Manager

Partnered with Indonesian policy makers and another BU student to evaluate the effectiveness of training programs in vocational schools

Designed an experimental evaluation of a government program Designed and implemented original surveys Managed and coordinated team of research assistants Developed training materials for research assistants Presented findings to policymakers

Bac-Credomatic Bank

2013 - 2014 Data Analyst

Designed and executed data analysis for the bank's senior management Identified, researched and facilitated the creation of data sets
Linked and profiled data from multiple sources to ensure accuracy & completeness
Worked closely with internal clients to provide data solutions & analysis
Created repeatable processes to update datasets in an automated way
Created and maintained robust documentation of solutions, validation testing & operating procedures for audit & compliance requirements

Teaching Experience

Teaching Fellow @ Boston University

2020 Economics of Labor Markets

Fall 2019 Poverty and Discrimination

2018 – 2019 Principles of Microeconomics

Instructor @ Universidad de Costa Rica

2014 – 2015 Principles of Economics

Developed lesson plans, homework, and grading schema

Wrote detailed feedback on homework and exams

Held weekly office hours for individualized tutoring

Fields of Interest

Labor Economics
Development Economics
Microeconomics
Applied econometrics

Skills

Project

Experimental design Long-term project management Team management Data visualization

Data

Use of large data Statistical analysis & testing Causal inference

Writing

Science writing Annotation guidelines

Technologies

R	••••
Stata	••••
MATLAB	••••
Git	••••
LAT _E X	••••
VBA	••••

Languages

English	
Spanish	L

Education

expected **Ph.D. Economics**

2023 Boston University, Boston, MA

2017 M.A. Economics & Finance CEMFI, Madrid, Spain

2013 **B.A. Economics**

Universidad de Costa Rica, San José, Costa Rica

References

References available upon request